Guide to the Doris Ulmann Photograph Collection ca. 1910-1934 PR 72
New-York Historical Society
- middle aged, bald, round eyeglasses, seated in DU's studio chair, suit, vest, tie, book in lap [Strauss, Samuel, Editor, The Villager], 156563 (Item 2655)
  #2655, 3002 same subject; subject is in "A Portrait Gallery of American Editors", but not this image
- older, white hair, mustache, in profile view, seated at desk or table, books or albums of some sort on desk or table, one arm resting on desk or table, suit, vest, tie, handkerchief in breast pocket, 156562 (Item 2656)
- middle aged, medium dark hair with gray at temple, suit, vest, tie, seated in profile at desk or table, down turned head resting on left hand, writing with right hand, 156561 (Item 2657)
- middle aged, stout, thinning medium light hair, suit, vest, tie, 156560 (Item 2658)
- older, white hair, mustache, beard, small oval eyeglasses, suit, vest, tie, seated with hands and papers on a desk or table, 1918; 156559 (Item 2659)
  oil or pigment transfer print
- young, thick wavy dark hair, parted in middle, handsome, suit, bow tie, seated, 156558 (Item 2660)
- middle aged, thinning white hair, bookshelf in background, jacket, vest, bow tie, 1918; 156557 (Item 2661)
- older to middle aged, white hair, suit, vest, tie, seated, cigar in hand, 156556 (Item 2662)
- older to middle aged, medium light hair, mustache, suit, vest, tie, arms crossed across chest, 156555 (Item 2663)
- middle aged, dark curly hair, gray at temple, seated, arms crossed across chest, double breasted jacket, tie, 1919; 156554 (Item 2664)
- young, thick medium dark hair, parted on side, seated with arms on desk or table, small book in hands, suit, vest, tie, looking away from camera, 156553 (Item 2665)
- young middle aged, light colored or white hair straight thick cropped short, suit, vest, tie, long striking face, suit, vest, tie, seated, hands on desk, bookcases in background [Van Doren, Carl, Editor, The Century], 156552 (Item 2666)
- young middle aged, light colored or white hair straight thick cropped short, suit, vest, tie, long striking face, suit, vest, tie, seated, arms on desk, bookcases in background [Van Doren, Carl, Editor, The Century], 156551 (Item 2667)
- young middle aged, light colored or white hair straight thick cropped short, suit, vest, tie, long striking face, suit, vest, tie, seated hands in lap, bookcases in background [Van Doren, Carl, Editor, The Century], 156550 (Item 2668)
- young middle aged, light colored or white hair straight thick cropped short, suit, vest, tie, long striking face, suit, vest, tie, seated hands in lap, bookcases in background [Van Doren, Carl, Editor, The Century], 156549 (Item 2669)
- young middle aged, light colored or white hair straight thick cropped short, suit, vest, tie, long striking face, suit, vest, tie, seated hands on desk, bookcases in background [Van Doren, Carl, Editor, The Century], 156548 (Item 2670)
- young middle aged, light colored or white hair straight thick cropped short, suit, vest, tie, long striking face, suit, vest, tie, seated hands in lap, bookcases in background, smiling [Van Doren, Carl, Editor, The Century], 156547 (Item 2671)
- young middle aged, light colored or white hair straight thick cropped short, dark round eyeglasses, suit, vest, tie, long striking face, suit, vest, tie, seated, holding cigarette, bookcases in background, smiling [Van Doren, Carl, Editor, The Century], 156546 (Item 2672)
- middle aged, very thin light colored hair, cleft chin, small oval eyeglasses, suit, vest, tie, seated hands clasped in lap, 156545 (Item 2673)
- older middle aged, thick white hair, round eyeglasses, in 3/4 view, light colored tweed jacket, vest, tie, seated behind desk or table in foreground, 156544 (Item 2674)
- two young men seated outside, in shirtsleeves, white man playing guitar, black man playing fiddle; two young women in foreground, seated on ground, both with dark wavy hair, one in flower print dress, on in medium dark colored dress with ruffled collar, 156543 (Item 2675)
  image is Fig. 37, page 101, caption reads: "Group of Four Kentucky Mount Musicians, Including African American Fiddler", 1932,. Platinum print. Alliance for the Guidance of Youth Collection, Special Collections, Duke University
- vegetable stand or grocery; stout middle aged woman, seated on crate, in apron; two young girls seated in front, one girl in flowered dress with dark straight short hair, 2nd girl in light colored dress with light colored short hair holding ear of corn, 156542 (Item 2676)
- older to middle aged couple seated on porch steps, both are stout, woman with hair pulled back, bangs, round eyeglasses mouth open as if talking, man with short white and gray hair, dark shirt, suspenders, leather apron, 156541 (Item 2677)
- older couple both seated in front of hearth, she in foreground, white hair, round eyeglasses, smiling, blankets (?) covering lap, he in background, long white beard, round eyeglasses, dark hat, light colored shirt, suspenders, hands on cane, 156540 (Item 2678)
- older couple, both thin, seated on porch, he in foreground, felt hat, cardigan, hands on knees, she in background in polka dot dress, hands in lap, 156539 (Item 2679)
- older couple seated in porch doorway, he foreground in wide brimmed straw hat, white beard, sideburns, mustache, clean work shirt, suspenders, cane, she in background, dark cardigan, med. dark color dress, medium dark hair, parted in middle, gaunt/sad, 156538 (Item 2680)
- young middle aged, light colored or white hair straight thick cropped short, suit, vest, tie, long striking face, suit, vest, tie, seated, hands in lap, bookcases in background [Van Doren, Carl, Editor, The Century], 156537 (Item 2681)
- young middle aged, light colored or white hair straight thick cropped short, suit, vest, tie, long striking face, suit, vest, tie, standing, map image on wall in background [Van Doren, Carl, Editor, The Century], 156536 (Item 2682)
- young middle aged, light colored or white hair straight thick cropped short, suit, vest, tie, long striking face, suit, vest, tie, seated, in profile, hands on desk, bookcases in background [Van Doren, Carl, Editor, The Century], 156535 (Item 2683)
- older, pretty thick straight white hair, mustache, beard, eyeglasses, knit cardigan, bow tie, seated, holding cane in one hand, folder newspaper in other, plants in background, 156534 (Item 2684)
- middle aged to older man, white and gray short hair, short stubbly beard and mustache, seated, light colored work shirt, suspenders, scratching chin looking deep in thought, 156533 (Item 2685)
- older, thin, pointed felt hat, white mustache, dark vest, clean work shirt, seated with hands in lap, 156532 (Item 2686)
- older man, tall wide brimmed straw hat, clean work shirt, suspenders, seated outside, plants in background, holding a folded newspaper, 156531 (Item 2687)
- group of men gathered around a table, watermelons on table, truck in background with man standing holding a melon, others are eating (?) or inspecting melons, one woman, lots of cut and eaten melons on ground, 156530 (Item 2688)
- young man standing among apple trees, straw hat, mustache, work shirt, suspenders, 156529 (Item 2689)
- older, seated on porch, dark wide brimmed felt hat, dark jacket, overalls, dark round eyeglasses, white bushy beard, sideburns, mustache, 156528 (Item 2690)
  #2690, 2691, 2696 same subject
- older, seated on porch, dark wide brimmed felt hat, dark jacket, overalls, dark round eyeglasses, white bushy beard, sideburns, mustache, 156527 (Item 2691)
- older, light colored felt hat, scraggly sideburns, eyeglasses, jacket, work shirt, leaning on crutches, 156526 (Item 2692)
- older, dark felt hat, very short beard, long mustache, work shirt, overalls, standing in doorway, 156525 (Item 2693)
- group in field; two young women in white collared dresses, dark hair pulled back, one standing with hoe, other kneeling, two men both with hoes or rakes, both dark hair, because of date and groomed look of group does not look like country folks, 1918; 156524 (Item 2694)
- middle aged, white hair, sideburns, beard; dark suit jacket, felt hat, seated outside, sideburns and beard look like image identified as Mennonite man in Jacob's book (plate 28, page 179 for example), holding book (bible?), 156523 (Item 2695)
  #2695, 2698, 2782, 2790, 2819 same subject
- older, seated on porch, dark wide brimmed felt hat, dark jacket, overalls, dark round eyeglasses, white bushy beard, sideburns, mustache, 156522 (Item 2696)
- older man, bald with longish white hair on sides and back, sideburns, long white beard, mustache, bushy eyebrows, 3/4 view, seated, dark jacket, work shirt, 156521 (Item 2697)
- older, white hair, sideburns, beard; dark suit jacket, felt hat, sideburns and beard look like image identified as Mennonite man in Jacob's book (plate 28, page 179 for example), 156520 (Item 2698)
- older, felt hat, short beard, mustache, work shirt, overalls, seated outside, 156519 (Item 2699)
- two men seated on platform next to porch in shade of trees, dappled light; one man facing away from camera with dark wide brimmed hat, other with mustache; basket and pale of apples and potatoes (?) in foreground, 156518 (Item 2700)
- middle aged, printer, visor, balding, oval eyeglasses, mustache, pipe in mouth, diamond/plaid patterned shirt, standing at bench or table with brayer in hand, 156517 (Item 2701)
- older, light colored top-hat type of hat, white sideburns, mustache, beard, corduroy or velvet jacket, seated in doorway, 156516 (Item 2702)
- older, seated outside in sunlight, vines on wall in background, felt hat, round eyeglasses, white or gray beard and mustache, work jacket, work shirt, 156515 (Item 2703)
- older, seated outside in front of stone walled building, large hat, round eyeglasses with black frames, white mustache, clean white work shirt, diamond patterned suspenders, leather satchel in lap, 156514 (Item 2704)
- young, dark short curly hair, handsome, husky, in work shirt, seated on bench, grape vines in background, bucket of cucumbers at side, holding a smallish ceramic or glass jug, 156513 (Item 2705)
- middle aged, longish straight dark hair and mustache, seated on high stool, suit, vest, tie, high shirt collar, holding a violin and bow, 1916; 156512 (Item 2706)
  #2706, 2715, 2716 same subject
- older, seated outside on step, door and shingled building behind, dark felt hat, plaid suit jacket, clean work shirt with dark buttons, pants with patches on knees, 156511 (Item 2707)
- middle aged to older, light colored cap, mustache and white beard, work shirt, suspenders, working at some kind of machine, looks like he's holding and filling a fabric sack under a hopper, 156510 (Item 2708)
  #2708, 2709 same subject
- middle aged to older, light colored cap, mustache and white beard, work shirt, suspenders, working at some kind of machine, looks like he's holding and filling a fabric sack under a hopper, 156509 (Item 2709)
- middle aged, standing in doorway, tattered hat, medium light mustache, smiling, striped work shirt, overalls, holding a pipe, 156508 (Item 2710)
- older, longish white straight hair, sideburns, mustache, no beard, seated, medium dark work shirt, 156507 (Item 2711)
- middle aged, painter seated at easel, landscape sketched on canvas behind, holding a large palette in left hand with brushes, long white or blonde hair, bangs, mustache, sideburns, beard [Dow, Arthur Wesley, artist and theorist (1857-1922)], 156506 (Item 2712)
- bald, white/white mustache, thick rimmed and thick lenses round eyeglasses, seated, suit, vest, tie [Hendrick, Burton Jesse, Editor, The World's Work], 156505 (Item 2713)
  #2110-2113, 2713, 2752, 2929 same subject, subject is in "A Portrait Gallery.. .", but not this image
- middle aged to older, bald, medium dark mustache, seated at writing table, open notebook, pencil in hand, books and eyeglasses on table, 1917; 156504 (Item 2714)
- two men, both middle aged; seated on wicker chair: longish straight dark hair and mustache, suit, vest, tie, high shirt collar; standing: top coat, light colored vest, tie, curly medium light colored hair, round eyeglasses, 1916; 156503 (Item 2715)
- middle aged, seated on wicker chair: longish straight dark hair and mustache, suit, vest, tie, high shirt collar, 1916; 156502 (Item 2716)
- young, musician, standing holding and strumming a very large guitar-like instrument, smiling, longish, thin straight hair, high collar, unusual bow tie, jacket, 156501 (Item 2717)
- unusual outdoor scene, two men, and artist and buyer in conversation in front of rows of canvases propped up against a building on a sidewalk; artist with beret, jacket, white shirt; "buyer" with dark hair, eyeglasses, suit, tie, 156500 (Item 2718)
- see 2718, possibly same place; artist seated at easel in what looks like daylight, sketching with vine of charcoal, looking right at camera, as if doing portrait; middle aged, bald, mustache, cleft chin, work shirt, 156499 (Item 2719)
- young, jacket, vest, tie, short, thick, straight salt and pepper hair, seated, looking intently into camera, a framed pencil or charcoal portrait of a young girl is partially visible in upper left corner hanging on wall [Van Doren, Carl, Editor, The Century], 156498 (Item 2720)
- couple both seated on porch; she: thin, gaunt-looking, thin gray hair parted in middle pulled back, dark cardigan, dark gray dress, holding cane or walking stick; he: wide brimmed straw hat, white sideburns, beard, work shirt, suspenders, holding cane, 156497 (Item 2721)
- group of 4 country men and Niles seated outside under a tree; Niles is writing in a note book, all are in shirtsleeves, some in overalls, two have hats [Niles, John Jacob, (1892-1980) folklorist, musician, Ulmann's assistant], 156496 (Item 2722)
- top hat, white tie, top coat, etc., holding overcoat, standing, walking stick [Niles, John Jacob, (1892-1980) folklorist, musician, Ulmann's assistant], 156495 (Item 2723)
- young middle age, straight medium dark hair, suit jacket with breast pockets on the outside, vest, tie, seated at desk, writing [Walsh, Richard J., editor, Collier's], 156494 (Item 2724)
  #1229-1231, 2143-2152, 2724, 2984 same subject, subject is in "A Portrait Gallery.. ." but not this image, mat is crumbling
- middle aged, balding, medium light short hair on sides and back, in profile, seated with hands on back chair, suit, tie, 156493 (Item 2725)
  other images of this subject in collection
- young, wiry, salt and pepper, curly disheveled hair, black bow-tie type tie, jacket, vest, seated on sofa, book base in background, 156492 (Item 2726)
  #2726, 2727 same subject, same sitting; other images of this subject in collection
- young, wiry, salt and pepper, curly disheveled hair, black bow-tie type tie, jacket, vest, seated on sofa, book base in background, 1919; 156491 (Item 2727)
- older, white straight hair, parted on side, mustache, seated with tree leaves in foreground, open book in lap, suit, vest, tie, high collar, a medal pinned to lapel, 156490 (Item 2728)
- older middle aged, thing, white straight hair parted in middle, round eyeglasses, jacket, vest, tie, stout, seated, arms crossed, in front of window, 1917; 156489 (Item 2729)
- young, very thick salt and pepper, but mostly dark, straight hair, mustache, round dark-rimmed eyeglasses, suit, vest tie, seated writing on pad propped on his knee, 156488 (Item 2730)
- young, dark thick wavy hair, striped double breasted suit, tie, seated on desk or bench, handsome, 156487 (Item 2731)
  there are other images of this subject in collection
- older, very white longish hair, balding on top, white sideburns, mustache, beard, suit, seated at desk, open book, writing on paper, cluttered bookcase in background, 156486 (Item 2732)
  #2732, 2738 same subject
- older middle aged, thin light gray hair, suit, vest, tie, 156485 (Item 2733)
- middle aged, short bushy hair, medium light, bushy eyebrows, checked suit, vest, tie, chrysanthemum in lapel, black armband, seated, open book in lap, book case in background [Thayer, William Sydney, M.D., LL.D., Hon. F.R.C.P.I., Professor of Medicine], 156484 (Item 2734)
- young, thin dark straight hair combed back, mustache, beard, round eyeglasses, striped shirt, tie, jacket, 156483 (Item 2735)
- middle aged, smooth, medium dark hair, suit, vest, tie, seated, 156482 (Item 2736)
- young, thick dark hair, round eyeglasses, suit, vest tie, holding book in hands, seated, 156481 (Item 2737)
  others of this subject in collection
- older, very white longish hair, balding on top, eyeglasses, white sideburns, mustache, beard, suit, seated at desk, 156480 (Item 2738)
- young (middle aged?), long white, very tousled, hair, dark eyebrows, seated, jacket, vest, white bow tie, animated, actor?, 156479 (Item 2739)
  #2739-2745 same subject
- young (middle aged?), long white, very tousled, hair, dark eyebrows, seated, jacket, vest, tie, cigar in ashtray in foreground, animated, actor?, 156478 (Item 2740)
- young (middle aged?), long white, very tousled, hair, dark eyebrows, seated, jacket, vest, white bow tie, looking forlorn, actor?, 156477 (Item 2741)
- young (middle aged?), long white, very tousled, hair, dark eyebrows, seated, jacket, vest, white bow tie, leaning back in chair, actor?, 156476 (Item 2742)
- young (middle aged?), long white, very tousled, hair, dark eyebrows, seated, jacket, vest, white bow tie, leaning sideways in chair, actor?, 156475 (Item 2743)
- young (middle aged?), long white, very tousled, hair, dark eyebrows, seated, jacket, vest, white bow tie, leaning sideways in chair, looking up over left shoulder, actor?, 156474 (Item 2744)
- young (middle aged?), long white, very tousled, hair, dark eyebrows, seated, jacket, vest, white bow tie, actor?, 156473 (Item 2745)
- bald, dark round eyeglasses, double breasted jacket [Wells, Thomas B., Editor, Harper's Magazine], 156472 (Item 2746)
  #1990, 2135-2142, 2746-2751, 2937, 2983 same subject, subject is in "A Portrait Gallery.. .", but not this image
- bald, dark round eyeglasses, double breasted jacket [Wells, Thomas B., Editor, Harper's Magazine], 156471 (Item 2747)
- bald, dark round eyeglasses, double breasted jacket [Wells, Thomas B., Editor, Harper's Magazine], 156470 (Item 2748)
- bald, dark round eyeglasses, double breasted jacket [Wells, Thomas B., Editor, Harper's Magazine], 156469 (Item 2749)
- bald, dark round eyeglasses, double breasted jacket [Wells, Thomas B., Editor, Harper's Magazine], 156468 (Item 2750)
- bald, dark round eyeglasses, double breasted jacket [Wells, Thomas B., Editor, Harper's Magazine], 156467 (Item 2751)
- bald, white/white mustache, thick rimmed and thick lenses round eyeglasses, seated, suit, vest, tie [Hendrick, Burton Jesse, Editor, The World's Work], 156466 (Item 2752)
  #2110-2113, 2713, 2752, 2929 same subject, subject is in "A Portrait Gallery.. .", but not this image; this image is a photogravure and appears to be a page from the book, identified on back
- middle aged, balding, straight white hair, sideburns, mustache, beard, pince nez eyeglasses, jacket, vest, tie, seated at desk writing [Abbott, Lawrence F., Editor, The Outlook], 156465 (Item 2753)
  #2753-2757, 2979 same subject; subject is in "A Portrait Gallery.. .", but not this image
- middle aged, balding, straight white hair, sideburns, mustache, beard, pince nez eyeglasses, jacket, vest, tie, seated at desk writing [Abbott, Lawrence F., Editor, The Outlook], 156464 (Item 2754)
- middle aged, balding, straight white hair, sideburns, mustache, beard, pince nez eyeglasses, jacket, vest, tie, seated open book in lap, pen or pencil in right hand [Abbott, Lawrence F., Editor, The Outlook], 156463 (Item 2755)
- middle aged, balding, straight white hair, sideburns, mustache, beard, pince nez eyeglasses, jacket, vest, tie, seated open book in lap, pen or pencil in right hand [Abbott, Lawrence F., Editor, The Outlook], 156462 (Item 2756)
- middle aged, balding, straight white hair, sideburns, mustache, beard, pince nez eyeglasses, jacket, vest, tie [Abbott, Lawrence F., Editor, The Outlook], 156461 (Item 2757)
- white hair, balding, gray suit, holding paper [Galsworthy, John (1867-1933) English writer], 156460 (Item 2758)
- middle aged, thinning medium dark colored straight hair, parted in middle, salt and pepper beard and mustache, bags under his eyes [Bridges, Robert, Editor, Scribner's], 156459 (Item 2759)
  #2175-2190, 2759, 2995 same subject, subject is in "A Portrait Gallery of American Editors", but not this image
- gray suit, vest, tie, smooth medium light hair, seated with book or notes on desk or table, cigar (?) in left hand, oval eyeglasses [Cosgrave, John O'Hara, Editor, the Sunday World], 156458 (Item 2760)
- straight dark hair, parted on side, pince nez eyeglasses, high collar, tie, white lab coat, seated at desk, hand on open book or notebook, desk lamp [Palmer, Walter W., Associate Professor of Medicine, Columbia], 1918; 156457 (Item 2761)
- seated in DU's studio chair, thin medium dark hair, high collar, mustache, holding eyeglasses [Adams, Henry Sherman, Editor, The Spur], 156456 (Item 2762)
  #2762-2768, 3012 same subject; subject is in "A Portrait Gallery of.. .", but not this image
- thin medium dark hair, high collar, mustache [Adams, Henry Sherman, Editor, The Spur], 156455 (Item 2763)
- seated in DU's studio chair, thin medium dark hair, high collar, mustache, holding book [Adams, Henry Sherman, Editor, The Spur], 156454 (Item 2764)
- seated in DU's studio chair, thin medium dark hair, high collar, mustache, holding book [Adams, Henry Sherman, Editor, The Spur], 156453 (Item 2765)
- seated in DU's studio chair, thin medium dark hair, high collar, mustache, holding book [Adams, Henry Sherman, Editor, The Spur], 156452 (Item 2766)
- seated in DU's studio chair, thin medium dark hair, high collar, mustache, holding and reading open book [Adams, Henry Sherman, Editor, The Spur], 156451 (Item 2767)
- seated in DU's studio chair, thin medium dark hair, high collar, mustache, holding book [Adams, Henry Sherman, Editor, The Spur], 156450 (Item 2768)
- older, seated outside, vines on wall in background, felt hat, rumpled jacket, vest, tie, white shirt, white beard and mustache, 156449 (Item 2769)
  #2769-2771 same subject
- older, seated outside, felt hat, rumpled jacket, vest, tie, white shirt, dirty and torn apron, shoe form (?) in hand, a cobbler?, white beard and mustache, 156448 (Item 2770)
- older, seated outside, trees in background, felt hat, rumpled jacket, vest, tie, white shirt, white beard and mustache, 156447 (Item 2771)
- young to middle aged, hat covered in bright sunlight, mustache, work shirt, overalls, seated, with a metal scoop, scooping grain from a large wooden grain measure, 156446 (Item 2772)
  on back of mount, in DU's handwriting: Doris Ulmann, 1000 Park Avenue, New York City, II The Miller; in other hand, blue pencil: U.1/6; on front of mat, lower left, pencil, not DU's hand: The Miller
- middle aged, tousled short dark hair, work shirt, overalls, standing in work yard, holding wheelbarrow with large wooden wheels, 156445 (Item 2773)
  #2773, 2865 same subject
- turned away from camera, standing holding lines from wagon on dock or deck of boat, striped shirt, cap, 156444 (Item 2774)
  possibly a pigment or oil transfer print, not platinum
- young middle aged, cap, striped work shirt, rolled up sleeves, standing at table or bench, appears to be kneading bread, 156443 (Item 2775)
- standing inside a granary full of grain, with shovel, wheel barrow in foreground, hat, work shirt, suspenders, 156442 (Item 2776)
- middle aged, hat, mustache, lanky, standing, white sweater-type shirt, boots, in a lumber yard, standing on pile of rough cut wood, holding a log with bark on it, 156441 (Item 2777)